export const quizQuestions_5 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is a correct way to create a functional component?',
      choices: ['const Component = function() { return <div />; }', 'function Component() { return <div />; }', 'Both A and B are correct', 'None of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both A and B are correct',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is PropTypes used for in React?',
      choices: ['To add default values to props', 'To type-check the props passed to a component', 'To document the purpose of each prop', 'To make all props required'],
      correctAnswer: 'To type-check the props passed to a component',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what is the children prop?',
      choices: ['A prop that defines child components to be rendered', 'A library for managing component hierarchies', 'A type of state in class components', 'A method to pass data between siblings'],
      correctAnswer: 'A prop that defines child components to be rendered',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you prevent a component from rendering in React?',
      choices: ['By returning null in the render method', 'By using the shouldComponentUpdate lifecycle method', 'By setting state to null', 'Both A and B'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both A and B',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the primary use of the React.memo() function?',
      choices: ['To memorize component state', 'To enhance component security', 'To optimize performance for functional components', 'To manage memory allocation'],
      correctAnswer: 'To optimize performance for functional components',
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the term “hoisting” refer to in JavaScript, which is often used in React?',
      choices: ['Lifting state up to a parent component', 'The process of moving function and variable declarations to the top of their containing scope', 'The practice of raising component state to a global level', 'A method for handling asynchronous operations'],
      correctAnswer: 'The process of moving function and variable declarations to the top of their containing scope',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the main use of the useEffect hook in functional components?',
      choices: ['To handle component lifecycle events', 'To manage component state', 'To create side effects in components', 'Both A and C'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both A and C',
    },
    {
      question: 'In a React component, what is the purpose of the key prop in a list of elements?',
      choices: ['To ensure each element in the list is unique', 'To improve rendering performance', 'To help React identify which items have changed', 'All of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the significance of the useState hook in functional components?',
      choices: ['It allows components to have their own state', 'It synchronizes state between multiple components', 'It replaces class components entirely', 'It is used to share state between components'],
      correctAnswer: 'It allows components to have their own state',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what does the term “immutability” refer to?',
      choices: ['A component’s ability to change its state', 'The practice of not changing the original state directly', 'The unchangeable nature of functional components', 'The fixed structure of a React application'],
      correctAnswer: 'The practice of not changing the original state directly',
    }
  ]
};
